[MARLEN] This peril
will strengthen the bonds
between temple and military.
And those very bonds
will ensure a path to victory
for all humanity.
Well said, Uncle.
Your words are inspiring
-and I will take them to heart.
-[MARLEN] Hmm.
May the blessings
of Saint Mahaeyzel
guide and protect us.
[Kivia gasps]
Now, let the attack commence.
[♪ tense music playing]
[Kivia breathes shakily]
[whimpers]
[metal rattles]
Uncle!
[MARLEN] Hmm?
[KIVIA] I'd like to learn more
about our current situation.
Who first reported
there were faeries in the city?
Which of the units?
Seven one one zero,
Ioff City Defense Force.
A few among them
managed to survive,
but they're in no condition
to talk.
[KIVIA] I would imagine not.
[MARLEN] If that is all.
[grunts softly]
[faeries shrieking]
[BOOJUM] They now
have an inroad
through the underground
waterway.
I suppose I should return
to the task at hand.
[thudding]
[faeries growling]
[♪ tense music playing]
[ZOFFLEC] Prepare for combat!
Sniper Captain Siena.
Do your best to slow them down.
[SIENA] Cavalry Captain Zofflec,
we've got this handled.
Ready? Fire at will!
[faeries shrieking]
[ZOFFLEC] Beautiful!
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
-[faeries growling]
[ZOFFLEC] Our turn!
Scatter them!
-[horses neighing]
-[knights yelling]
[horses neighing]
We'll follow
and take out any foes they miss!
Secure the area!
[KNIGHTS] Yes, sir!
[knights yelling]
That will do.
At least we can entrust
this task the Holy Knights.
Meanwhile, we
must keep investigating
Demon Lord Spriggan.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[faeries growling]
[shrieks]
Tatsuya, go!
-[Tatsuya grunts]
-[faerie growls]
[Tatsuya yells]
[grunts]
[yells fiercely]
[screams]
-[faerie growls]
-[Tatsuya yells]
[grunts]
-Huh?
-[men gasp]
-[MAN 1] That must be a faerie!
-[MAN 2] A humanoid.
[MAN 1] Fighting its own?
We're all human here.
Now open the door.
Human?
[MAN 2] That sacred seal.
-He's a penal hero.
-[door thuds]
[XYLO] Let us in already!
The faeries
will summon reinforcements.
You want to live or die?
[men grunt softly]
[XYLO] You'll be easy pickings
hiding in your little shelter.
[TEORITTA] We must utter words
of inspiration.
Civilians, heed my words!
Hmm.
Lay down your fear,
for I am the goddess Teoritta.
I offer salvation,
thus I must ask you
to follow our lead.
[RHYNO] That's right.
We're here to help.
Your shelter is in a rather
precarious position.
But there's absolutely
no need to worry.
The Shining Goddess of Swords,
Teoritta,
and the Thunder Falcon,
Xylo Forbartz,
are here to save the day!
-[MAN 3] She's a goddess?
-[MAN 4] The Thunder Falcon?
[MAN 5] They really exist?
-[XYLO] Knock it off!
-[RHYNO] Whoopsie!
Where'd you hear
about that crap?
[RHYNO] Those rumors managed
to reach even my lonely cell.
You've become something
of a living legend!
-Are you stupid or what?
-Enough, my knight!
Please control your temper.
We are the Shining Goddess
of Swords
and the Thunder Falcon!
-[Tatsuya grunts]
-How grand.
Our monikers are quite fitting
-for champions of legend.
-[Xylo grunts]
[Tatsuya growls]
[Xylo sighs]
[exhales]
We'll need to prepare them
to defend themselves.
Rhyno, teach them
how to use the lightning staves.
[RHYNO] Of course.
It would be my pleasure.
I'll strive to make you proud,
Comrade Xylo.
If you don't mind,
I'd like your advice
on something.
What?
[RHYNO] Which civilians
would make the best
cannon fodder here?
-[exclaims] Come again?
-[RHYNO] The elderly
are clearly the most expendable,
don't you think?
They've already had their shot
at life,
which gives them an edge
over the children.
-I'd say the fairest option--
-That's enough.
Don't tell me you really
thought I'd go along with that.
[RHYNO] Huh? Do you view it
as a moral quandary
or some such?
Look, we're here on a mission.
We won't rest
until we've exhausted
every possible option.
Losing civilians
-is the absolute last resort.
-[faeries growling]
[♪ tense music playing]
Reinforcements already?
[JAYCE] Xylo, still
haven't done your job, eh?
Always a step behind.
It's looking like I'm about
to score another win.
[faeries shriek]
[Neely roars]
[RHYNO] Comrade Jayce!
Comrade Neely!
Allow me to thank you
for your brave service
on behalf of our evacuees.
Shut your mouth, asshole.
Alright, Dotta. Who's up next?
[DOTTA] Well, about that.
I've got bad news!
There's someone
in scary black armor
on the red tower!
[grunts]
Artillery? Neely!
[RHYNO]
They've got tracking shells?
Our dragoon
won't be of much help to us.
[grunts]
Rhyno, I'm taking the fight
to Tui Jia.
You and Tatsuya
protect this warehouse
to the death.
[RHYNO] A brilliant plan!
We'll join forces
to overcome this trial
for the greater good.
It would kill me
to disappoint you.
My whole world
would suddenly be devoid
of meaning.
Stop being so creepy.
Or at least try.
[RHYNO] Well, then.
[people gasp]
[RHYNO] Come!
Let us forge a bond
in the embers
of courage and duty.
We'll fight side by side.
And risk everything
for the sake of humanity!
Well? Unexpected.
That dragoon
must be a nimble rider
to outfly my barrage.
We can't afford
to have that pesky dragon
flying around, causing trouble.
So, Iron Whale,
can you rid us
of our little problem?
[WHALE] I can.
But only if you take care
of the ones on foot.
Artillery and close-range combat
don't mix.
And you? Planning to take
on the goddess killer?
Yes. He's quite powerful.
A foe worthy of my respect.
[WHALE] You're an unusual one,
aren't you?
I expected you
Demon Blight freaks
to be a lot colder
and more savage.
[BOOJUM] That is true
of many of us.
But I am not one of them.
I bear no hatred towards humans.
Their impending doom
makes them that much more worthy
of my respect and pity.
-[explosion]
-[BOOJUM] That is one thing
I dislike
about Spriggan’s methodology.
The complete lack of respect.
It has become apparent
that the only one who truly
appreciates my perspective
is my king.
[WHALE] Your king?
So even Demon Lords have lords.
[BOOJUM] Hmm.
Ah, I've said too much.
This conversation is over.
-[metal rattles]
-[Whale laughs]
I wouldn't dream of prying.
In my business,
people who know too much
are the first
on the chopping block.
[BOOJUM] The goddess killer
is approaching.
I have a particular fondness
for humans like him.
But I must kill him.
Everything I do
is for my king.
[footsteps approaching]
[RAJIT] Captain Kivia.
We secured the area
around the government buildings.
So what
should we prioritize next?
Huh.
Captain Kivia?
[KIVIA] New plan.
I need you three
to handle things here.
[RAJIT] Hmm?
[KIVIA] I have
some important business
to tend to.
[RAJIT] Hmm.
I'm sorry.
That's all I can tell you.
-[RAJIT] I understand.
-[gasps softly] Huh.
[RAJIT] I pledged
to serve my captain
to the bitter end,
come what may.
The odds were against us
at Couvenge as well.
And don't forget, you're the one
who taught me how to fight.
So my sword is yours.
[Kivia gasps softly]
[RAJIT] I'll return to my post.
-Hey, Rajit.
-Yes?
Listen.
In case something happens to me,
there's something
you need to know.
[rumbling]
[RHYNO] Comrade Xylo,
I'm in position.
[XYLO] Those people
had better still be alive.
[RHYNO] Alive and kicking.
Everything is going beautifully.
Comrade Tatsuya
is in his element.
[♪ heroic music playing]
[RHYNO] I didn't know
he was adept
at using lightning staves.
We should be grateful
someone as competent
as him is on our side.
We owe that man a debt
of gratitude.
[XYLO] Venetim! Is Tsav ready?
[VENETIM]
There's been a slight delay
on that front. But speaking of,
you should know
the faeries have reached
the inland district.
[Xylo grunts]
Teoritta, are you ready?
Yes. Let us fight
for all of humanity.
[Xylo scoffs] You realize
we could both die
in this battle?
And you're not a hero.
So if you fall,
you won't be coming back!
Each of your deaths
demands a heavy toll.
The loss
of more precious memories.
And I will not allow it.
I need
to safeguard those treasures.
You need only concern yourself
with protecting my life.
[scoffs]
Nothing could be more asinine
than risking your life
for someone else's.
Regardless, it's a deal!
[growling]
[XYLO] Let's win this thing!
[whoosh]
We'll wrap up before morning
and celebrate over breakfast.
Zeff butter
on some freshly baked bread.
With a hot bowl of onion soup
and a side of crispy bacon.
[XYLO] You goddesses
certainly have a knack
for motivation.
Now I'm hungry as hell!
[roars]
Don't worry.
You're much faster
than those stupid shells.
They won't hit you!
The hell are you waiting for?
An invite?
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] Seriously?
[faeries shrieking]
-[grunts]
-Xylo.
-What shall we do?
-Forge ahead.
There's no other path.
Cut them down!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[grunts] Here we go!
[TEORITTA] Rain of blades!
[shattering]
Teoritta, don't let up! [grunts]
[grunts]
[SHIJI BAU] Don't be stubborn.
[Xylo gasps]
-My knight.
-I've got this.
Hey, that
was a pretty nasty trick!
That's what I was hired for.
[grunts]
This time I won't hold back!
[swords clink]
-[Xylo grunts]
-[Teoritta gasps]
Iron Whale, a little backup,
but you'd better not hit me.
[WHALE] Honestly,
it's always something with you!
[TEORITTA] My knight, allow me.
[grunts] She's gone?
[Shiji Bau grunts]
[grunts]
-Die!
-Teoritta! Do it now!
[Shiji Bau gasps]
[yells fiercely]
Jayce, are you ready?
Always. Looks
like an easy victory.
[grunts]
[JAYCE] Neely!
[Neely growls]
[XYLO] Say goodbye!
[screams]
[WHALE] Damn.
That's what happens
when I'm distracted!
[XYLO] Rhyno, have you locked
on to the target?
[RHYNO] But of course.
My calculations are complete
and my target is distracted.
Havoc time.
[Whale gasps] Artillery?
That doesn't make sense!
This is beyond artillery!
-How could they--
-[explosion]
[Venetim whimpers]
That's going to be a tough one
to explain.
My goodness. The tower.
I know. That was the plan.
-Hmm.
-[XYLO] Let's fly.
[BOOJUM] There you are.
[FRENCI] That's twice now
you've sought my help.
Treating a night-gaunt
as your personal spy.
It is uncouth.
Besides, my hands are full
with the search
for Demon Lord Spriggan.
I don't have time
to explore other options.
Help me!
I'll pay any price.
And the moment
I discover the truth--
-[FRENCI] Consider it done.
-[Kivia gasps]
Huh.
[FRENCI] I will have
your answers by morning.
Oh.
I'm grateful.
It is for Xylo's sake,
as he will soon join
the Mastibolt family.
And for me.
A captain of the Holy Knights
owes me a favor now.
That will surely come in handy.
Farewell.
[footsteps receding]
[♪ tense music playing]
Stand strong and fire!
[faeries shrieking]
Don’t relent!
-[DOTTA] Majesty!
-Fire!
[DOTTA] Incoming!
A bogie horde this time.
A huge one!
Might be a good idea to retreat?
-No retreat!
-[gasps]
[NORGALLE] Take one step
from your watchtower
and I will hang you for treason!
[sighs]
[NORGALLE] Put
that superior vision to work.
That is why I entrusted you
with Tsav's lightning stave!
[Dotta grunts]
That thing's way too big
and clunky!
The least you can do
is hold your position.
Tsav will be here shortly.
[DOTTA] How do you know
if he's really coming, though?
- I wouldn't if I were him.
-Silence!
He may be a lonely villain,
but even he
is above fleeing from battle.
Wait. That makes it sound
like you think
I'm a worse kind of villain
-than he is.
-[NORGALLE] There was a time
- when I believed you were.
-Huh?
But I've been told that despite
all your foolishness,
you have been known
to make miracles happen.
Such was the report
of my commander in chief.
Hold out,
and victory will be ours.
As the king,
it is my sacred duty
to choose worthy retainers
and trust them implicitly.
-[whoosh]
-[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] Take that!
[BOOJUM] Your reaction speed
is truly incredible.
You're exceeding
my expectations,
Xylo Forbartz.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
That's blood.
[BOOJUM] You've proven yourself
to be a formidable opponent.
But if there's even
the slightest chance
I'm able to slay
that goddess of yours,
I have to at least try.
Right?
[Xylo grunts]
[♪ tense music playing]
Great. Can't get close.
Jayce, little help?
[JAYCE] I can't see my target
through the splattered blood
and dust.
Unless you don't mind us
frying you guys, too.
Of course I mind! [grunts]
Rhyno, what are you waiting for?
Start firing!
[RHYNO] I'm afraid my line
of sight is obstructed as well.
I'll have to recalculate.
But don't worry yourself.
The tower will fall soon enough.
[XYLO] Damn it!
They're completely useless.
We're on our own.
Fine by me.
[grunts]
[both gasp]
[Teoritta exclaims]
-[Xylo grunts]
-[Teoritta exclaims]
To hell with you! [grunts]
No, my knight!
[BOOJUM] I see
you've stopped fighting.
Now it's time to die.
The goddess Teoritta.
Of all these lives...
yours is the one
I must extinguish at any cost.
-[Xylo grunts]
-[gasps]
[XYLO] Don't worry.
You think I'd let that happen?
Trust in your knight.
And never doubt
for a moment that we'll prevail!
-[TEORITTA] Hmm.
-[XYLO] Believe I'm invincible
and I will be.
[BOOJUM] Xylo Forbartz!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[BOOJUM] What's this?
[XYLO] It's over, Boojum.
You lose.
[BOOJUM] A valiant effort.
But I'm afraid you're mistaken.
I'm not finished yet!
[grunts]
-[TEORITTA] You are injured!
-[XYLO] It's nothing.
[grunts]
[XYLO] This feels right.
[♪ dramatic music continues]
I'm fighting...
like I used to in a past life.
[panting]
One more time.
[Xylo pants]
[XYLO] How long
will my body hold up?
How much can she take?
I have to finish this.
Try to read Boojum's movements.
I won't lose.
It's foolish to fight for glory.
I have to save them.
This isn't over yet!
I will end you!
[BOOJUM] Magnificent!
[♪ heroic music playing]
[BOOJUM] Brilliant execution,
Xylo Forbartz.
With your skill and courage,
you would have made
a fine subject for an epic poem.
Precisely the kind of work
I enjoy most.
Too bad.
I fear that is also the reason
I must do everything
in my power to destroy you.
Spiraling Blood.
Noble knight,
-you shall not be defeated.
-Agreed!
It is time.
Let us end this.
[XYLO] This
will be the final blow!
Think I can do it?
Naturally.
Your goddess
demands that you prevail.
Break free of your limits!
[grunts] You got it!
[BOOJUM] At the behest
of my king, I must kill!
[yells fiercely]
[BOOJUM] You know
you can't defeat me.
[sword clinking]
[Boojum grunts]
It can't be.
He's wielding
the world-ending Holy Sword!
[yells fiercely]
[TEORITTA] There is nothing
the Holy Sword cannot destroy.
And that includes you.
[sword clinks]
[Xylo pants]
[sizzling]